<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2026-02-21T09:32:10-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Meta Currents</title><subtitle>Meta Currents is a blog about the latest trends in technology, programming, and software development. We cover a wide range of topics, including web development, mobile app development, artificial intelligence, machine learning, and more. Our goal is to provide our readers with the most up-to-date information and insights on the latest developments in the tech industry. </subtitle><author><name>aliencoder</name></author><entry><title type="html">Some online mattress retailers are actually safe</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/story1/2019/01/02/1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Some online mattress retailers are actually safe" /><published>2019-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/story1/2019/01/02/1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/story1/2019/01/02/1.html"><![CDATA[I was recently in the market for a new mattress, and, like any normal
      person, I searched what was available online.&nbsp; As it turns out, (as
      of September 2018), there are a number of different online retailers
      peddling their wares.&nbsp; A google search today for "mattress" today
      revealed the following sponsored links in the following exact order:</p>
    <ol>
      <li><a href="saatvamattress.com">saatvamattress.com</a></li>
      <li><a href="nectarsleep.com/%3F">nectarsleep.com/&#8206;</a></li>
      <li><a href="amazon.com/mattresses%3F">amazon.com/mattresses&#8206;</a></li>
      <li><a href="bestmattressonline.org/reviews%3F">bestmattressonline.org/reviews&#8206;</a></li>
    </ol>
    <p>The following are the next 5 unsponsored links, which means their rank in
      the search result is mostly driven by the weight given to them by google
      page rank algorithms.</p>
    <ol>
      <li><a href="mattressfirm.com/">mattressfirm.com/</a></li>
      <li><a href="casper.com/mattresses/">casper.com/mattresses/</a></li>
      <li><a href="purple.com/mattresses">purple.com/mattresses</a></li>
      <li><a href="costco.com/mattresses.html">costco.com/mattresses.html</a></li>
      <li><a href="wayfair.com/bed-bath/cat/mattresses-c414871.html">wayfair.com/bed-bath/cat/mattresses-c414871.html</a></li>
      <li><a href="ikea.com/us/en/catalog/categories/departments/bedroom/Mattresses">ikea.com/us/en/catalog/categories/departments/bedroom/Mattresses</a>/</li>
    </ol>
    <p>However, my original search process for a mattress did not lead me to
      purchase the mattress with the highest precedence on search.&nbsp; Rather,
      my decision was more influenced by the numerous ads that began to appear
      on e-commerce and social media platforms. It was truly these ads that
      played a larger role in my decision making.&nbsp; User cookies play a
      larger role than one might originally imagine in world of
      e-commerce.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
    <p>After reading several articles and watching many review videos on
      youtube, I settled on the fairly well-known Leesa mattress.&nbsp; My end
      conclusion at the time of purchase is that most mattresses are about the
      same but Leesa does have a mission of caring and giving back to the
      community.&nbsp; If I were to pay a premium on a mattress, at least some
      of my cash would go towards helping someone who needed help getting
      appropriate bedding(or so my reasoning went). &nbsp; </p>
    <p>Alas, it turns out the mattress was not really worth the price tag that I
      paid for it, and my sleep did not improve noticeably.&nbsp; Hence, I made
      a call to the Leesa customer service after giving the new mattress a fair
      chance (studies and retailers say to give at least 30-60 days).&nbsp; By
      answering 2 short questions, and with a hold time of less than 2 minutes,
      a call time of less than 4 minutes,&nbsp; I was able to schedule a pick up
      for my mattress within the next 2 weeks. &nbsp;&nbsp; There was no
      pushback of any sorts by the customer representative, and this was
      refreshingly appreciated.&nbsp; </p>
    <p>I am thoroughly impressed by Leesa's customer service and would recommend
      anyone in the market for a new mattress to give them a chance if they are
      swayed by reviews and their own research.&nbsp; They are, so far, a
      company that can be trusted.&nbsp; I will update this post when the
      mattress has been picked up and my monies refunded.</p>]]></content><author><name>aliencoder</name></author><category term="story1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I was recently in the market for a new mattress, and, like any normal person, I searched what was available online.&nbsp; As it turns out, (as of September 2018), there are a number of different online retailers peddling their wares.&nbsp; A google search today for "mattress" today revealed the following sponsored links in the following exact order: saatvamattress.com nectarsleep.com/&#8206; amazon.com/mattresses&#8206; bestmattressonline.org/reviews&#8206; The following are the next 5 unsponsored links, which means their rank in the search result is mostly driven by the weight given to them by google page rank algorithms. mattressfirm.com/ casper.com/mattresses/ purple.com/mattresses costco.com/mattresses.html wayfair.com/bed-bath/cat/mattresses-c414871.html ikea.com/us/en/catalog/categories/departments/bedroom/Mattresses/ However, my original search process for a mattress did not lead me to purchase the mattress with the highest precedence on search.&nbsp; Rather, my decision was more influenced by the numerous ads that began to appear on e-commerce and social media platforms. It was truly these ads that played a larger role in my decision making.&nbsp; User cookies play a larger role than one might originally imagine in world of e-commerce.&nbsp;&nbsp; After reading several articles and watching many review videos on youtube, I settled on the fairly well-known Leesa mattress.&nbsp; My end conclusion at the time of purchase is that most mattresses are about the same but Leesa does have a mission of caring and giving back to the community.&nbsp; If I were to pay a premium on a mattress, at least some of my cash would go towards helping someone who needed help getting appropriate bedding(or so my reasoning went). &nbsp; Alas, it turns out the mattress was not really worth the price tag that I paid for it, and my sleep did not improve noticeably.&nbsp; Hence, I made a call to the Leesa customer service after giving the new mattress a fair chance (studies and retailers say to give at least 30-60 days).&nbsp; By answering 2 short questions, and with a hold time of less than 2 minutes, a call time of less than 4 minutes,&nbsp; I was able to schedule a pick up for my mattress within the next 2 weeks. &nbsp;&nbsp; There was no pushback of any sorts by the customer representative, and this was refreshingly appreciated.&nbsp; I am thoroughly impressed by Leesa's customer service and would recommend anyone in the market for a new mattress to give them a chance if they are swayed by reviews and their own research.&nbsp; They are, so far, a company that can be trusted.&nbsp; I will update this post when the mattress has been picked up and my monies refunded.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Major US gov sites affected by shutdowns</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/12/30/1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Major US gov sites affected by shutdowns" /><published>2018-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/12/30/1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/12/30/1.html"><![CDATA[</p>
    <p>I noted that the following sites are no longer being updated due to the
      current shutdown- </p>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://www.usa.gov/">https://www.usa.gov/</a> - innocuously
        named, but primarily provides information about the US government </li>
    </ul>
    <p>Their full mission statement can be found <a href="https://www.usa.gov/history-of-website">here</a></p>
    <p>"We create and organize timely, needed government information and
      services and make them accessible to the public anytime, anywhere, via
      their channel of choice."</p>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://www.nps.gov/index.htm">National Park Service</a> -
        availability of parks and protection of wildlife are probably one of the
        lower concerns </li>
    </ul>
    <p>
      However, some websites are more equal than others and are operating
      normally.&nbsp; </p>
    <ul>
      <li><a href="https://www.irs.gov/">https://www.irs.gov/</a> - tax
        collection </li>
      <li><a href="https://www.army.mil/">https://www.army.mil/</a> - military </li>
      <li><a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/">https://www.whitehouse.gov/</a>
        - propaganda </li>
      <li><a href="https://www.cia.gov/">https://www.cia.gov/</a> - intelligence
      </li>
    </ul>
    <p><br>
    </p>
    <p>A full list of government sites is available here </p>
    <p><a href="https://www.usa.gov/federal-agencies/%20">https://www.usa.gov/federal-agencies/
        </a></p>
    <p>It's quite astounding how many agencies are part of the federal
      government.&nbsp; This is probably why the federal budget(deficit) is so
      astounding.</p>]]></content><author><name>aliencoder</name></author><category term="story1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I noted that the following sites are no longer being updated due to the current shutdown- https://www.usa.gov/ - innocuously named, but primarily provides information about the US government Their full mission statement can be found here "We create and organize timely, needed government information and services and make them accessible to the public anytime, anywhere, via their channel of choice." National Park Service - availability of parks and protection of wildlife are probably one of the lower concerns However, some websites are more equal than others and are operating normally.&nbsp; https://www.irs.gov/ - tax collection https://www.army.mil/ - military https://www.whitehouse.gov/ - propaganda https://www.cia.gov/ - intelligence A full list of government sites is available here https://www.usa.gov/federal-agencies/ It's quite astounding how many agencies are part of the federal government.&nbsp; This is probably why the federal budget(deficit) is so astounding.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What Dell going public could mean for consumers</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/12/29/post7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What Dell going public could mean for consumers" /><published>2018-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/12/29/post7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/12/29/post7.html"><![CDATA[<p>Dell is going public again without holding an IPO. The arrangement to do
      so is a bit complex but has been summarized by experts as a share buyback
      of VMWare (of which Dell owns a majority stake in). The infograph by <a href="https://vizologi.com/business-strategy-canvas/dell-business-model-canvas/">Vizologi&nbsp;</a>
      shows most of Dell's revenue comes from its selling of support services
      and computing devices to consumer. </p>
    <p>This arrangement means non-corporate and general investors can now buy
      shares of the company on the New York stock exchange. As for consumer
      products, I would expect to see strong performance in consumer laptops,
      desktops, and tablets as demand for newer and more power efficient
      hardware increases. The Dell XPS series is an excellent and highly rated
      laptop series. The Alienware series is also very popular with gamers and
      the high end market, especially with lower cost effectiveness of
      performing custom builds(buying components on sale notwithstanding).
      VMWare, though a leader in the industry, may see some disruption from
      Citrix and Microsoft as they continue expanding their server
      virtualization services. </p>
    <p>All in all, although I expect Dell will continue to offer a decent
      product offering, its long term business viability depends on its ability
      to react efficiently to consumer demands. </p>
    Major Dell products and offerings:
    <ul>
      <li>Laptops </li>
      <li>Desktops </li>
      <li>Workstations </li>
      <li>Monitors </li>
      <li>PC Accessories </li>
      <li>Servers </li>
      <li>see more at <a href="www.dell.com">Dell</a></li>
    </ul>
<p>
    disclosure: This article is for informational purposes only and is not an offer to buy or sell any security. It is not intended to be financial or tax advice, and it is not financial or tax advice advice. Before acting on any information contained herein, be sure to consult your own financial or tax advisor.
</p>]]></content><author><name>aliencoder</name></author><category term="story1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Dell is going public again without holding an IPO. The arrangement to do so is a bit complex but has been summarized by experts as a share buyback of VMWare (of which Dell owns a majority stake in). The infograph by Vizologi&nbsp; shows most of Dell's revenue comes from its selling of support services and computing devices to consumer. This arrangement means non-corporate and general investors can now buy shares of the company on the New York stock exchange. As for consumer products, I would expect to see strong performance in consumer laptops, desktops, and tablets as demand for newer and more power efficient hardware increases. The Dell XPS series is an excellent and highly rated laptop series. The Alienware series is also very popular with gamers and the high end market, especially with lower cost effectiveness of performing custom builds(buying components on sale notwithstanding). VMWare, though a leader in the industry, may see some disruption from Citrix and Microsoft as they continue expanding their server virtualization services. All in all, although I expect Dell will continue to offer a decent product offering, its long term business viability depends on its ability to react efficiently to consumer demands. Major Dell products and offerings: Laptops Desktops Workstations Monitors PC Accessories Servers see more at Dell disclosure: This article is for informational purposes only and is not an offer to buy or sell any security. It is not intended to be financial or tax advice, and it is not financial or tax advice advice. Before acting on any information contained herein, be sure to consult your own financial or tax advisor.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">new github A name records</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/12/27/post8.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="new github A name records" /><published>2018-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/12/27/post8</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/12/27/post8.html"><![CDATA[Githubpages has new A records which support https,

The old ips
A @ 192.30.252.153
A @ 192.30.252.154

The new ips should be
A @ 185.199.108.153
A @ 185.199.109.153
A @ 185.199.110.153
A @ 185.199.111.153

However, the new IPs could cause your site to stop performing adequately.]]></content><author><name>aliencoder</name></author><category term="story1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Githubpages has new A records which support https,]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A stranger through a city</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/03/02/post6.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A stranger through a city" /><published>2018-03-02T12:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-03-02T12:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/03/02/post6</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/story1/2018/03/02/post6.html"><![CDATA[<p>The window banged into my head and woke me up from my drifting
      sleep. The bus was slowing down for its next stop but the window
      sized potholes in the street were too much for the bus's old suspension
      system to smooth out.</p>
    <p>"53rd and Park," the bus operator called out over the tinny speaker
      system. An elderly woman covered in long trench coat slowly made her
      way to the front, thanked the driver and exited the bus. Once safely
      cleared, 3 noisy teenagers climbed aboard.</p>
    <p>"Yo, I'm telling you, that's what happened. Why won't you believe
      me man?" a lean boy with long black hair pleaded with his two
      friends. They both began to laugh as they took their seats on the
      bus.</p>
    <p>"You always tell the tallest tales! You're like a professional
      storyteller. You should go into showbiz. I'm sure you'll
      make millions" the taller boy retorted.</p>
    <p>"Dude, you are a bigger liar than Trump, heck, forget that, a bigger liar
      than Hillary!" a chubbier boy added. The long black haired boy shook
      his head with disbelief.</p>
    <p>"It's up to you if you don't believe me! Your loss!" he exclaimed.</p>
    <p>The bus started moving again and entered on to the highway. The
      next stop wouldn't happen for at least 15 minutes depending on highway
      traffic conditions. I looked out over the ramp and saw an endless
      stream of cars packed tightly. I sighed. It would be at least
      an hour before I would be able to make it home. This would be the
      3rd time this month that I had missed the early bus and settled for the 6
      o clock. I bundled up my hoodie and wedged it under my head between
      the window and the headrest. It was quite comfortable and
      warm. I could even fall asleep if the seats on the bus weren't so
      upright. </p>
    <p>As the bus began its stop-and-go journey through the 4 lane gridlock, I
      drifted asleep again to the sound of the bus's soft engine. My mind
      slipped back to my meeting from 5 weeks ago which had led me to be where I
      was now.</p>]]></content><author><name>aliencoder</name></author><category term="story1" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The window banged into my head and woke me up from my drifting sleep. The bus was slowing down for its next stop but the window sized potholes in the street were too much for the bus's old suspension system to smooth out. "53rd and Park," the bus operator called out over the tinny speaker system. An elderly woman covered in long trench coat slowly made her way to the front, thanked the driver and exited the bus. Once safely cleared, 3 noisy teenagers climbed aboard. "Yo, I'm telling you, that's what happened. Why won't you believe me man?" a lean boy with long black hair pleaded with his two friends. They both began to laugh as they took their seats on the bus. "You always tell the tallest tales! You're like a professional storyteller. You should go into showbiz. I'm sure you'll make millions" the taller boy retorted. "Dude, you are a bigger liar than Trump, heck, forget that, a bigger liar than Hillary!" a chubbier boy added. The long black haired boy shook his head with disbelief. "It's up to you if you don't believe me! Your loss!" he exclaimed. The bus started moving again and entered on to the highway. The next stop wouldn't happen for at least 15 minutes depending on highway traffic conditions. I looked out over the ramp and saw an endless stream of cars packed tightly. I sighed. It would be at least an hour before I would be able to make it home. This would be the 3rd time this month that I had missed the early bus and settled for the 6 o clock. I bundled up my hoodie and wedged it under my head between the window and the headrest. It was quite comfortable and warm. I could even fall asleep if the seats on the bus weren't so upright. As the bus began its stop-and-go journey through the 4 lane gridlock, I drifted asleep again to the sound of the bus's soft engine. My mind slipped back to my meeting from 5 weeks ago which had led me to be where I was now.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">creating content</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/writer's-block/2018/03/01/post5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="creating content" /><published>2018-03-01T12:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-03-01T12:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/writer&apos;s-block/2018/03/01/post5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/writer&apos;s-block/2018/03/01/post5.html"><![CDATA[<p>I can do it.&nbsp; I can write!&nbsp; I have so many great ideas to share
      and people will want to read what I write.&nbsp; That is what I told
      myself when I started to write for a blog.&nbsp; But when the time came to
      actually put ink on paper, or in this case type text between &lt;p&gt;s,
      the task was much more daunting, and doubt creeps in.&nbsp; Who would want
      to read what I write on this corner of the internet.&nbsp; There is a
      whole internet out there for people to read!&nbsp; Reddit, Wikipedia,
      Facebook, Twitter.&nbsp; Who has time for traditional blog reading
      nowadays anyway.&nbsp; It, especially, will not be people listening to
      podcasts or those endlessly watching cat videos on loop on YouTube(I think
      I already use that expression too much).&nbsp; But, alas, I must remind
      myself- the blog created here is not particularly meant to read to be
      consumed by a large unknown, uncaring, and usually quite critical,
      crowd.&nbsp; Rather, it is nothing more than an exercise in my creative
      ability in the hopes that it will leave me feeling fulfilled.&nbsp;</p>
    <p>But that cannot be the only goal that is achieved.&nbsp; If my ideas were
      to resonate with some reader, perhaps then they may nod their heads in
      agreement and perhaps lead to a certain sort of epiphany for them.&nbsp;
      In any case, this blog can hopefully function as a public journal to semi
      stream-of-consciousness sort of blabbering.&nbsp; There isn't even a spell
      check that I am using right now!</p>
    <p>&nbsp;</p>]]></content><author><name>aliencoder</name></author><category term="writing" /><category term="writer&apos;s-block" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I can do it.&nbsp; I can write!&nbsp; I have so many great ideas to share and people will want to read what I write.&nbsp; That is what I told myself when I started to write for a blog.&nbsp; But when the time came to actually put ink on paper, or in this case type text between &lt;p&gt;s, the task was much more daunting, and doubt creeps in.&nbsp; Who would want to read what I write on this corner of the internet.&nbsp; There is a whole internet out there for people to read!&nbsp; Reddit, Wikipedia, Facebook, Twitter.&nbsp; Who has time for traditional blog reading nowadays anyway.&nbsp; It, especially, will not be people listening to podcasts or those endlessly watching cat videos on loop on YouTube(I think I already use that expression too much).&nbsp; But, alas, I must remind myself- the blog created here is not particularly meant to read to be consumed by a large unknown, uncaring, and usually quite critical, crowd.&nbsp; Rather, it is nothing more than an exercise in my creative ability in the hopes that it will leave me feeling fulfilled.&nbsp; But that cannot be the only goal that is achieved.&nbsp; If my ideas were to resonate with some reader, perhaps then they may nod their heads in agreement and perhaps lead to a certain sort of epiphany for them.&nbsp; In any case, this blog can hopefully function as a public journal to semi stream-of-consciousness sort of blabbering.&nbsp; There isn't even a spell check that I am using right now! &nbsp;]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How much ram do you need in 2018</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/computers/general/2018/02/28/post4.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How much ram do you need in 2018" /><published>2018-02-28T12:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-02-28T12:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/computers/general/2018/02/28/post4</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/computers/general/2018/02/28/post4.html"><![CDATA[<p>How much ram do you really need? 8gb? 16gb? 64gb? What about a monstrous 128gb?</p>
<p><strong>Short answer</strong></p>
<p>As much as you can afford, because more is always better, and the additional power draw is negligable in this case.</p>
<p><strong>Long Answer</strong></p>
<p>If you're shopping for a laptop, you are likely to see ads for laptops that have usually 8gb or 16b configurations.&nbsp; If price is no object, then it usually makes sense to buy a machine with as much ram as possible to 'future-proof' it as much as possible.&nbsp; However, quite often, the extra ram may not be useful if you don't actually use it for anything.&nbsp; For web browsing and watching cat videos on youtube 8gb, or even 4gb on a windows machine will be more than sufficient.&nbsp; Most smartphones that are released in 2018 actually tend to have less than 4gb of ram as well.&nbsp; One of the differences between phones and desktops is that phones are more aggressive at suspending, or terminating unused applications in the foreground.&nbsp; Usually the phones that tend to have more ram have more advanced capabilities to run applications in true multitasking containers.</p>
<p>Personally, I buy the largest sticks of ram possible that are accepted by my motherboard.&nbsp; I currently have 2x16gb of ram in my desktop.&nbsp; However, I have never come close to utilizing even half of it.&nbsp;&nbsp; But of course, I have a habit of closing unused applications.&nbsp; At the time of writing, I am running a virtual box instance, and a chrome browser on a Windows 10 host machine.&nbsp; Task manager reports that chrome is using 2.3gb of ram, while the virtual box manager is using ~0.1gb.&nbsp; It seems that the usage by&nbsp; ubuntu virtual machine does not appear in windows Task Manager.&nbsp; This should be something that could need to be fixed or it might be a 'feature' of virtualbox. &nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]></content><author><name>aliencoder</name></author><category term="computers" /><category term="general" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[How much ram do you really need? 8gb? 16gb? 64gb? What about a monstrous 128gb? Short answer As much as you can afford, because more is always better, and the additional power draw is negligable in this case. Long Answer If you're shopping for a laptop, you are likely to see ads for laptops that have usually 8gb or 16b configurations.&nbsp; If price is no object, then it usually makes sense to buy a machine with as much ram as possible to 'future-proof' it as much as possible.&nbsp; However, quite often, the extra ram may not be useful if you don't actually use it for anything.&nbsp; For web browsing and watching cat videos on youtube 8gb, or even 4gb on a windows machine will be more than sufficient.&nbsp; Most smartphones that are released in 2018 actually tend to have less than 4gb of ram as well.&nbsp; One of the differences between phones and desktops is that phones are more aggressive at suspending, or terminating unused applications in the foreground.&nbsp; Usually the phones that tend to have more ram have more advanced capabilities to run applications in true multitasking containers. Personally, I buy the largest sticks of ram possible that are accepted by my motherboard.&nbsp; I currently have 2x16gb of ram in my desktop.&nbsp; However, I have never come close to utilizing even half of it.&nbsp;&nbsp; But of course, I have a habit of closing unused applications.&nbsp; At the time of writing, I am running a virtual box instance, and a chrome browser on a Windows 10 host machine.&nbsp; Task manager reports that chrome is using 2.3gb of ram, while the virtual box manager is using ~0.1gb.&nbsp; It seems that the usage by&nbsp; ubuntu virtual machine does not appear in windows Task Manager.&nbsp; This should be something that could need to be fixed or it might be a 'feature' of virtualbox. &nbsp;&nbsp; &nbsp; &nbsp;]]></summary></entry></feed>